<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life management | notbenh yaks about stuff on the internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/blog/categories/life-management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-11T23:12:19-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://notbenh.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[notbenh (aka ben hengst)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tracking time should not be hard]]></title>
    <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/blog/2013/06/03/tracking-time-should-not-be-hard/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T16:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://notbenh.github.com/blog/2013/06/03/tracking-time-should-not-be-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I go thru bouts of trying really hard to be organized. I am going thru another
such event and have decided to dust off my old time tracking script. It
effectively is a journal of context changes that are stored in such a way that
timing can be inferred from. I still like the concept but the interface was
overly complex and the reporting was not able to deal well with anything more
then a single day.</p>

<p>Thus time to open up the hood and get to hacking. I'll save the details for
another post if I really want to go down that rabbit hole, instead I would
rather focus on usage.</p>

<p><code>
  time.pl personal:blog write about time tracking
</code></p>

<p>So the key here is that the first 'word' is expected to be the project. Any
use of : is to denote a sub project, in this case I am working on this very
blog post. Like I said: simple.</p>

<p>So that's great, <em>slow clap</em> it's simple but how is this time tracking?
Great observation, the secret sauce is that what time.pl is doing here is it
is taking note of the time and then adding both a timestamp and every thing to
a single log file:</p>

<p><code>
  [Mon Jun 3 18:02:35 PDT 2013] personal:blog write about time tracking
</code></p>

<p>So now I am writing the post, but when I am done I am going to then have some
dinner. Thus when I change context, I just make a note of it.</p>

<p><code>
  time.pl off dinner
</code></p>

<p>Because each entry is stamped, we can code a report that will do the diff for
each entry and the 'next' and infer the amount of time that was spent on it.
In effect just track your context changes, and let the robot do the work for
you. EXACTLY!</p>

<p>As a bonus, to make all of this possible you end up with a journal of
everything you did in the day. For me I use this as habit tracking. Do I
really spend that much time on email? Wow, I spent over an hour on coffee
breaks today. Congrats, you spent more then 2 hours on personal projects!</p>

<p>All of this is possible by noticing when you change context and making a
little note of it.</p>

<p>If you wanna play along the code is all up on <a href="https://github.com/notbenh/TimeTrax">github</a> feel free to play along.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
