<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: community | notbenh yaks about stuff on the internet]]></title>
  <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/blog/categories/community/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T20:40:52-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://notbenh.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[notbenh (aka ben hengst)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[check your habits]]></title>
    <link href="http://notbenh.github.com/blog/2014/01/13/check-your-habits/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T18:57:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://notbenh.github.com/blog/2014/01/13/check-your-habits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2013 was a great year for me to do some deep self assessment, come to
terms with emotions. Over all 2013 was a rough year and given the state
of 2014 thus far, I have yet to decide if it has been any better. The
upside though is that adversity is how you grow. I have taken the past
year to really dig in to what makes my brain tick, I have been picking
up philosophy and psychology books like they are going out of style.
Some of them have, others have not. I am a slow reader so I have yet to
get thru everything but it has helped me become more aware of my self.
I feel that I am far more in sync with my own emotions. Thus I have
come to a concussion: people, in general, are just shitty to each other.</p>

<p>The key to this conclusion is the 'in general' part. Because the world
is complex, the brain builds subroutines and shortcuts to help make
sense of the world. Why reprocess a bunch of data when you already can
assume the answer? Your pet dog comes in to the room, does your brain
start to ponder if this is a threat? Mine doesn't, it's my dog Trek and
he either wants to go out side, snug, or play. These shortcuts are known
as habits but they are not limited to pets. At least in my brain, I have
habits that help me make meals, I have habits on getting from place to
place. I have so many habits that I could not even begin to count them,
and this is by design, they are subconscious. These are compiled
subroutines that are executed with out conscious interaction.</p>

<p>I had a few paragraphs here about how habits help but you get the point.
The key is when we take habits to the next level and abstract out from
our daily life. Do all cops hate blacks? Do all whites fear blacks? Do
all politicians lie? Do all republicans hate gays? Do all lesbians hate
men? Do all men have a lesbian fantasy? The list goes on and honestly
the answer to every one of these generalizations is no. If you think
about it for just a few seconds you can think of at least one person
that you know that would refute each one of these absolute statements.
Again because the world is complex our brain has built shortcuts, but
that is all that it is a shortcut. Your brain makes a generalization for
some reason and you go on living your life focusing on what your brain
feels is more important. Are members of the football team bullying you?
It might make sense to fear a football jersey. But if the last time that
happened was 20 years ago and you still fear a football jersey, is that
really the appropriate emotion for the stimulus? Just as you clean out
your closet from time to time it is healthy to question why you have the
assumptions and shortcuts that make you, well you.</p>

<p>This is not to say that chaining a habit is easy, but awareness is simple
to obtain and it is the start to any type of change. All you have to do is
ask why when you notice that you did anything that feels like it just
happened. Watching TV and happen to flip by a football game and you all
of sudden get all amped up for seemingly no reason, ask your self why.
Introduced to a person of another race, instantly have a presumption about
them, why? Feel that you are inferior to that guy for cubes over who you
have never really met but just seems intimidating... why? The trick is to
not just stop at the first answer, but to keep asking why, keep going until
there really is not a good answer to the simplest question in the world.
Be your own nagging 3 year old:</p>

<ul>
<li>Woah I just avoided that whole group of teens at the mall!</li>
<li>Why? Well they looked scary.</li>
<li>Why? There were like 12 of them.</li>
<li>Why does that matter? Well I guess it doesn't.</li>
<li>Ok so why did you avoid them? I guess it was that one big guy?</li>
<li>So do you think you have a fear of big guys? Guess so?</li>
</ul>


<p>Does this imply that you have resolved anything? No! But becoming aware
helps you make better decisions despite your emotional reaction to
things. For example if you know that you have a habitual fear of large
men, then that might explain why you generally avoid that guy a few cubes
over? He might have never talked to you, never been in a meeting with
you but if he goes to the gym then you might have already determined
that he is out to get you with no evidence.</p>

<p>If you do not come to terms with your own bias, if you do not question
your own habits from time to time. Then you will be just as guilty as
any one else and at some point you will find your self being shitty to
some one else just because of a silly little habit of yours. It sucks
but, hay, the world is a complex place, right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
